Back in the days of our youth,
まだ幼かった
あのころの私たちにとって
世界は驚異と威厳に満ちていた
the world seemed grand and full of dangers.
だが それも大きくなって
But once we had grown older and acquired our Canti,
呪力を手に入れさえすれば
怖いものなど 何１つ無くなるはず
we felt that nothing would be able to scare us anymore.
そう固く信じていた
We believed that from the bottom of our hearts.
Based on my observations of the battlefield,
現場の状況から判断して
the losses in this battle were split ten to zero.
今回の戦闘における損害の割合は
10対０
塩屋虻コロニーによる
完全な勝利です
The Robber Fly colony achieved a perfect victory.
Most of what remained of the Giant Hornet soldiers were severely mutilated,
破れた大雀蜂軍兵士たちの遺体は
どれも損壊が激しく
ほぼ原型を留めていないといった
状態です
to the point where they were reduced to lumps of flesh.
How could the military power of the
Giant Hornets be wiped out so easily?
あの強大な軍事力を誇る
大雀蜂コロニーが
こうも簡単に…
As for Kiroumaru,
奇狼丸の件ですが
遺留品などから総合的に判断し
judging from evidence left at the scene, it is safe to conclude that he managed to escape,
戦闘地域からの離脱には
成功したものと思われますが
今 現在も消息は 一切不明です
but his whereabouts are currently unknown.
それから今回の件に関係あるか
どうか分かりませんが…
Also…
Well, I'm not sure if it's relevant.
何かしら？
What is it?
None of the dead Giant Hornet soldiers had any sort of weapon on them.
大雀蜂軍兵士たちの遺留品に
武器が１つも無かったんです
Even if we suppose that the victorious Robber Flies took their weapons,
勝者である塩屋虻側が
持ち去った可能性もあるかと思い
common sense would dictate that we should find unusable ones on the battlefield.
その場合 使い物にならない武器は
戦場に放置されるのが
通常なのですが…
その… とにかく…
At any rate, there was nothing that could be called a weapon.
武器という武器が
全て無かったんです
I see. Thank you for your report.
そう 分かったわ ありがとう
今の報告内容から
何か思い当たることはある？
Does anyone have an idea based on this information?
昨日 現場に行ってみましたが
既に証拠隠滅が図られ
I went to the scene myself yesterday,
but it had already been wiped clean of possible evidence.
完全に炭化した状態でした
Doesn't that suggest they have something to hide?
わざわざ
そんなことをしたということは
何か 後ろ暗いことが
あるからかしら？
これについて
私なりの意見はありますが
I have my own theory regarding that,
but as I have no proof, I'd like to present it last.
確証があるわけでは
ありませんので
最後に申し上げたいと思います
Would it be safe to say the Robber Flies wished to hide their means of attack?
塩屋虻コロニーは その攻撃手段を
隠したかったのでは
ないでしょうか？
Peace and Cooperation
Saki!
早季！
あっ…
I thought we agreed to meet over there.
あそこで待ってるって
言ったじゃないか…
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
そうだっけ？
We did?
ハァ… 今年の化け物は
結構 凝ってるな
The monsters this year are quite elaborate, don't you think?
ああっ… もうっ！
Hey!
Look, there!
ほらあれ！
何よ？
What?!
ああっ ねえ！ ちょっと！
Hey, wait!
Scarlet
Flower
Episode
Eighteen
僕 あの大きいの欲しい
ねっ 兄ちゃん 取ってよ
I want that big one!
Catch it for me, Bro!
おっ こっち来た よ～し
All right! It's swimming this way!
おそろいだね
They match!
Yeah, they do!
うん おそろいだね
化け物が来たら
食べられたりしないかな？
What if a monster comes? Will it eat us?
大丈夫だよ
本当？
Don't worry. It won't.
Really?
I think so…
たぶん…
逃がしてあげよっか？
Want to free them?
Yeah.
早季！
あっ…
Saki!
あ… ほら見て
え？
Look, there.
ほら あそこ 子供の化け物！
Right there.
A child monster.
どこ？
Where?
Over there.
ほら あそこ あそこだってば！
Can't you see it?
Your eyes must be deceiving you.
見間違いじゃないの？
子供が化け物の役するなんて
聞いたことないぞ
I've never heard of the monsters being played by children.
じゃあ 今年から
そうしたんじゃないの？
Well, maybe they started this year?
バケネズミの
最近の急速な進歩と軍備拡張は
The rapid technological and military advances of the queerats indicate they have some source of information.
彼らが 何らかの情報源を
得ている可能性を示しています
それは ミノシロモドキのこと？
You mean a false minoshiro?
Yes.
はい…
旧国会図書館の移動式端末は
It is possible that a number of the old National
Assembly Library's mobile terminals are still operational.
まだ 数機が
生き残っている可能性があります
バケネズミたちは
それらを捕獲して
The queerats may have caught them and
are perhaps extracting information from them.
知識を得ているのかも知れません
Then, Mizuho-chan, tell us as Head of the Library.
それで 瑞穂ちゃん
図書館司書としての見解は
どうなのかしら？
大雀蜂の兵士たちを いとも簡単に
全滅させられるような手段が
Would there have been a way for them to
annihilate the Giant Hornet army so easily?
存在するのかしら？
禁書… 第４分類の…
Class four forbidden documents…
The third category of class four
forbidden documents, “catastrophe,”
第４分類の第３種 ｢殃｣に属する
項目によれば
確かに 古代文明には
describes several different weapons of mass destruction.
数種類の
大量破壊兵器が存在しました
それらを使用することによって
Such a weapon would be capable of the
immediate annihilation of a queerat army.
バケネズミの軍団を
瞬時に壊滅することは可能です
That was not the work of bombs.
あれは 爆弾などによるものでは
ありませんよ
はぁ… きれい…
So pretty…
真理亜！
Maria!
ハァ ハァ ハァ…
真里亜！ どこ？
Maria!
Where are you?!
Maria…
真里亜…
Saki…
早季…
No…
違うの…
But… she was there…
でも… 確かに いたの
守も… 顔の無い少年も…
Mamoru and the faceless boy were there, too…
これは 先日の
実地検分で発見された
These are arrows of the Giant Hornet soldiers that we found during our inspection that day.
大雀蜂軍の矢です
何か お気付きになりませんか？
Does anything appear noteworthy to you?
These arrows are entirely undamaged.
この矢には
全く損傷が見られません
他の物も全て同じです
These are not the exceptions either.
イヒッ…
Every single Giant Hornet arrow on the battlefield was undamaged.
現場に残された
大雀蜂軍 全ての矢は
どれも
同じ状態で残されていました
確かに… 仮に
爆弾などが使用されたら
You’re right.
Bombs would have damaged the arrows.
こんな きれいに残りません
ええ
Yes.
でも…
通常 攻撃に使用された矢は
But…
Wouldn’t any arrow be damaged once loosed, regardless of whether it hit or missed?
当たっても外れても
何らかの損傷を
受けるはずではないでしょうか？
Under normal circumstances.
通常ならば そうでしょう
The only way I can explain undamaged arrows
常識的に考えて
完全に無傷な矢など
is that they were stopped mid-flight by Cantus.
呪力によって 空中で
止められたものくらいなものです
肆星 もったいつけないで！
Shisei, don’t drag this out.
あなたは
何があったと思ってるの？
What is your theory?
不遜のそしりを受けても
あえて 申し上げましょう
I hope I have your forbearance as I say this.
大雀蜂軍を全滅させたのは
呪力を持った人間です
The Giant Hornet army was annihilated by a human using their Cantus.
That theory also lines up with Asahina-kun’s report.
確かに そう考えると
朝日奈君の報告も
整合性が取れてきますね
So a human used their Cantus to
disarm the entire Giant Hornet army?
呪力を持った人間が
大雀蜂軍 全ての武器を
無力化したということですか？
But that’s quite a difficult—
しかし それは 相当 高度な…
この町をはじめ 他の どの町にも
No one in this or any other town would do that.
そんなことをする人間は
１人もいないわ
それは私が保証します
I can guarantee that.
ならば 過去に町から出ていった
人間は どうでしょうか？
What about the ones who left the town a long time ago?
How do you explain their remains?
あの遺骨は どう説明するの？
今となっては
それすら疑わしくなっている
At this point, I’m beginning to doubt those too.
なぜなら その遺骨を
発見したと称して届け出たのは
This is because the one who brought us those remains was none other
今回の事件の元凶と思われる
あの野孤丸だからです
than whom I suspect to be the puppet master of this atrocity, Yakomaru.
It will take some time, but I believe that convincing bones could be arranged.
工作には多少の時間が
かかりますが
うまく行けば お骨も
用意できるかもしれません
それを届ければ
たぶん ご納得いただけるかと…
They will most likely understand if presented those.
私どもの骨でも部位によっては
Portions of our skeletons cannot be reliably told apart from yours.
神様のものと見分けが
つかないことがございます
とりわけ長身の者であれば
The tall ones of our race are similar in height to a young god.
若神様とは 大きさも
さほど変わりません
ですので その骨を念入りに
石で こすりまして…
We will carefully chafe their bones with stones…
We can be certain they were their bones.
あの骨は 間違いなく本物だったわ
We examined the remains as thoroughly as possible.
遺骨は 慎重の上に慎重を期して
鑑定させたのよ
人間の骨であること
年齢と性別に矛盾はないか
They were human bones.
There were no inconsistencies in age or gender.
そしてＤＮＡ鑑定…
The DNA matched as well.
結局 決め手になったのは
The dental records that were kept at Harmony School put it beyond reasonable doubt.
和貴園に保管されていた
２人の歯形だったわ…
つまり 秋月 真里亜と
伊東 守の２人は
It is absolutely certain that Akizuki Maria and Itou Mamoru are dead.
すでに100％死亡したことが
確認されているの
よって あの２人は無関係です
Hence, they cannot be connected to this.
早季… 俺だって同じだよ
Saki… I feel the same.
たとえ幽霊だって
I want to see them if I can, even if they’re just ghosts.
真里亜たちに
会えるものなら会いたいさ
でも…
But…
I wasn’t imagining things.
気のせいなんかじゃないの…
いたの
She was there.
ああ 君には見えてたんだと思う
Yeah. I’m sure you saw her.
でも早季は 祭りに来る前から
But that was what you expected before we even got here, right?
真里亜たちに会えると
思っていただろ？
どうして？
What makes you think that?
Your yukata. It’s nothing like last year’s.
浴衣だよ
去年とは全然違う… まるで喪服だ
You look like you’re in mourning.
Today the dead return from the underworld.
今日は 冥土から
みんなが帰って来るんだ
I’m not surprised you saw them.
別に おかしなことじゃないよ
Were you able to meet them, Saki?
早季は真里亜たちに会えた？
Yeah.
塩屋虻コロニー および
それに同盟するコロニーの
All committees have approved of the complete
annihilation of the Robber Fly colony and all its allies.
バケネズミについては
全てを駆除 抹殺することで
全会一致の承認とします
This will be carried out by the team of Wildlife Protection officers that Inui here is heading.
実行については
ここにいる乾氏を筆頭に
鳥獣保護官が
速やかに実行すること 以上！
That is all.
すいません 最後に１つ提案が…
Excuse me, I wish to suggest one more thing.
The Summer Festival is scheduled to be held a week from now,
１週間後の夏祭りですが
安全が確認されるまで
but I suggest we postpone it until the situation has stabilized—
延期すべきではないかと…
却下！
Rejected!
たかが バケネズミどもに
おびえて
I can’t believe you’re suggesting we postpone an eagerly
anticipated event because you’re scared of some pitiful queerats!
せっかく楽しみにしていた祭りを
延期するなど
言語道断！ この臆病者が！
You coward!
他に質問はないですね？
では解散！
There are no other questions, I expect.
Dismissed, then.
I thought the festival would be
postponed as well after all the chaos.
今年は あんなことがあったから
祭りも延期になると思ってたけど
やっぱり やって良かったよ
I’m glad it wasn’t.
Yeah.
あっ… ほら あれ…
Hey, look!
ね いたでしょ？
See, I was right.
ホントだ
I guess so…
変だな… 何で蚊が
八丁標の中にいるんだ？
Weird.
Why are there mosquitoes inside the Holy Barrier?
乾さんたちが
戻って来たんじゃない？
Maybe Inui-san’s team is back.
終わったのかな？
So they’re done?
うん 塩屋虻の駆除って
確か 今日が期限だったでしょ
Yeah.
Weren’t they scheduled to clean up the Robber Fly group by today?
あっ 覚！
え？
Satoru!
Someone… Someone collapsed!
人が… 人が倒れてる！
死んでる…
He’s dead.
え？ まさか さっきの子供が？
Don’t tell me that child…
That wasn’t a child.
子供じゃない… バケネズミだ
It was a queerat.
No way! That can’t be!
そんな！ ありえないわ！
They realized they’d be butchered anyway,
so they decided to launch a last-ditch attack.
どうせ皆殺しにされると覚悟して
イチかバチかの勝負を
仕掛けてきたんだろう
じゃあ 塩屋虻が？
Then the Robber Flies are…
We have to tell the others!
みんなに知らせないと！ うっ…
何？ 花火が！
What’s that? Fireworks?
No!
違う！
Die!
くたばれ！
ギャ～ッ！
Stop!
やめて！
それより 早く逃げなくちゃ
We have to get out of here!
はっ！ そうか…
I see!
広場を挟み撃ちにするつもりだ！
They want to surround and attack the town square!
There must be more of them this way.
この向こうにも
まだ いる可能性が高い
広場の方へ行こう
でも 広場は…
Let’s go to the square!
But the square—
Don’t worry.
大丈夫 広場の人たちが
そのまま やられるはずがない
The people there would never go down so easily.
They’ve probably turned the fight around already.
たぶん
もう形勢は逆転してるはずだ
STOP
干渉を避けるため
皆さんは呪力を封印してください
To prevent interference, please refrain from using your Cantus.
この場は私が受け持ちます
I will handle this.
Wow…
すごい…
ヒャッヒャッヒャ…
人をだました悪ネズミ
You are bad little rats to have deceived us.
舌を引き抜き 裏返し
Should I tear out your tongues? Turn you inside out?
Dry you out in the sun like fish?
天日に干して 干物にしようか？
Or maybe I’ll crush your bones, stretch your bodies
like dough and make a triple-layered mochi out of it!
はたまた 骨を砕いて引き伸ばし
３段重ねで餅にしようか？
ウキ～！
Why was the gang earlier coming from upwind?
さっきの やつら 何で風上から…
ウソ… ああっ…
I knew it!
やっぱり そうか！
They’re using poison gas! Be careful!
毒ガスです 気をつけてください！
I see, I see!
そうか そうか
教えてくれて ありがとう
Thanks for telling us.
I suppose they aren’t complete idiots!
まんざら バカでもなかったか
Upwind?
風上？
I kept wondering why they attacked from upwind instead of coming from downwind and locating us by sense of smell.
ずっと気になってたんだ
何で さっきの やつらが
においで こちらの位置を探れる
風下じゃなくて
風上から攻めてきたのか！
ふんっ！
ギャ～！
I can’t believe it!
信じられない…
風向きを変えるなんて
They turned the wind around?
ああ ホントだ…
Yeah, they did.
いよお～っ はっ！
うお～！ いいぞ～！
そ～れっ はっ よっ はっ
そ～れっ たあっ へっ よっ…
ああ…
キャ～！
くっ… 外道
You filth!
ああっ！
キャアッ…
Die!
散れ！
Did you think your camouflage would trick me?
擬態などで この私の目が
ごまかせると思ったのか？
You dirty rats!
この ネズミどもが！
Hang in there.
しっかりしろ
バカな… この私が…
Unbelievable…
Those little rats actually got me…
ネズミごときに…
I’m sorry. I was careless.
すまん 私が油断しなければ…
Why are the children of Heaven given such frail bodies?
なぜ… 神の申し子が
こんなに もろい肉体…
The art within me is losing its flame…
私の中の芸術が
息絶えてしまう…
なんと もったいない
What a waste.
May you see beauty…
美の残像を…
The immediate danger has passed.
当面の危機は去りました
However, do not allow yourselves to let your guard down.
しかし 依然として
予断を許さない状態です
安全保障会議メンバーの方は
All present members of the Defense
Committee are to gather immediately.
おられましたら
速やかに集合してください
以後の行動は非常事態訓練どおり
Hereafter you are to follow your training for states of emergency.
５人１組でお願いします
Form your groups of five.
If your group is missing members, merge with another group.
欠員が出た場合は
速やかに他の組に合流し
Never walk with less than five.
決して
５人未満にはならないように
Patrol the town once your group has gathered,
先にできた組から 町を巡回し
残っているバケネズミを
しらみ潰しにしてください
and eliminate every last remaining queerat in the streets.
Saki!
Should they try to claim that they belong to loyal colonies,
早季！
お母さん！
Mom!
ignore what they say and destroy them.
お父さんは？
Where’s Dad?
Don’t worry.
大丈夫 無事よ
He’s fine.
医療関係者の方は集合願います！
I request all medical staff to gather here.
移動が困難な患者の方は
公民館の方へ お願いします
Please move all immobilized
patients to the community center.
Tomiko-san!
富子さん！
あっ 鳥飼さんは？
Where is Torigae-san?
She was always the most anxious and the most cautious of us.
いちばん心配性で
いちばん慎重なコだった…
In retrospect, Hiromi-chan was the only one who
suggested that we postpone the Summer Festival.
今にして思えば 宏美ちゃんだけが
｢夏祭りは延期すべきだ｣って
言ってたのに…
全人学級のときの１班は
もう 俺たち２人だけだ
We’re the only ones left from Group One when we were at Sage Academy.
どこかと合流しよう
Let’s join up with another group.
What’s on your mind?
何を考えてるの？
分からない でも…
I don’t know.
But my anxiety is gnawing away at me.
なんだか 心配でたまらないんだ
くれぐれも気をつけてね 早季
Please be very careful, Saki.
Don’t split up, thinking your Cantus will keep you safe.
呪力があるからって
絶対にバラバラになるんじゃない
いいね？
Got it?
分かった 大丈夫
Yeah. Don’t worry.
あの悪鬼 Ｋと遭遇して以来
I don’t remember having felt this much hatred since the fiend called K.
これほど強い憎しみを
覚えたことはないわ
忌まわしいバケネズミ 野狐丸には
The despicable queerat called Yakomaru will have to pay.
必ず この報いを
受けさせなくてはなりません
約束しましょう
I vow to subject him to agony no
living being has ever suffered before
いまだ かつて どんな生き物も
味わったことのないほどの
苦痛の中で
ゆっくり 命を奪ってやることを
as he dies a slow, protracted death.
秋月 真理亜 14歳
I’m Akizuki Maria, and I was 14…
…when I fled Kamisu’s 66th district together
.with Itou Mamoru twelve years ago.
12年前に神栖66町より
伊東 守と共に逃亡後
We were both confirmed dead afterwards.
両名 共に死亡が確認される
I loved you, Saki.
早季が好きだった…
でも 守を１人にはできないし
But I couldn’t abandon Mamoru,
どのみち
あの町では生きていけない
and I could no longer live in that town anyway.
それに…
女同士じゃ子供は作れないわ
And well, we can’t have kids since we’re both girls.
そうよ ねえ？
That’s right.
Yeah?
そうでしょう？
Am I right?
Nani mo iranai
何もいらない
I need nothing else
Anata ga ireba ii
あなたがいればいい
When you are by my side
Sotto yokogao iki wo korosu
そっと横顔 息を殺す
I look at you in profile and hold my breath
Mabataki sureba kieteshimaisou de
まばたきすれば消えてしまいそうで
I'm afraid it might vanish like an illusion if I blink now
Mitsumesasete suki da yo
凝視めさせて好きだよ
Let me look at you, I love you
Ah kigi ga furue furidashita yuki
ああ 木々が震え 降り出した雪
The trees shake in the wind and snow gathers on the ground
Ashiato futatsu shiroku
足跡 ふたつ 白く
Two lines of white footprints show
Toki yo tsumore
時よ 積もれ
Snowflakes of time, gather
Kami ni mune ni futari dake no yume ni
髪に 胸に ふたりだけの夢に
In our hair, our hearts, our dream
Sakenai hana no
咲けない花の
This flower cannot bloom
Tane wa yuki ni dakare
種は雪に抱かれ
And the snow embraces its seeds
Yorisou no
寄り添うの
As they huddle together
Shizuka ni wasureraretai
静かに忘れられたい
Quietly they wish to be able to forget
FROM
THE
NEW
WORLD
うわ～！ くそっ くるな～！
Damn it! Stay back!
あれは 一体 何なんだ！
What the hell is that?!
Run…
逃げろ 早く…
Hurry…
あいつが戻ってくるぞ！
He’ll be back!
He? Who?
｢あいつ｣って 誰なんですか！
何があったんですか！
What happened?!
Darkness